Frances Densmore papers
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 11: Photographs, All photograph titles were composed by Judith Gray, based on her research.; All digital files for Series 11 can be found within the same digital object identifier: afc1944002.
  - Subseries 1: Lantern slides, Slides AFC1944/002: PH001 to PH050 were used by Frances Densmore in a lecture in Minot, South Dakota in 1935.
    - Neah Bay, Washington, AFC 1944/002: PH022; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Cropped form of AFC 1944/002: PH074 (Box 12)
    - Singers pounding on planks (Makah), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 124, plate 19c, AFC 1944/002: PH023; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Possibly Neah Bay, Washington, AFC 1944/002: PH024; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Annie Long Tom (Clayoquot), similar to Plate 6a in Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 124, AFC 1944/002: PH025; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Charles Swan in dance costume (Makah), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 124, Plate 4b, AFC 1944/002: PH026; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Slahal game in progress, hop-picking camp in Chilliwack, British Columbia, similar to Plate 8 in Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 136, AFC 1944/002: PH027; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Papago house at San Xavier, cropped form of Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 90, Plate 2c, AFC 1944/002: PH028; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Well and water trough at San Xavier, Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 90, Plate 2b, AFC 1944/002: PH029; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Desert near Baboquivari Mountain, see, example, Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 90, Plate 5 (shape of mountain), AFC 1944/002: PH030; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Sivariano Garcia, Harry Encinas, and Jose Panco pounding basket drum (Papago), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 90, Plate 7b, AFC 1944/002: PH031; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Jose Panco using scraping sticks with basket resonator (Papago), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 90, Plate 7a, AFC 1944/002: PH032; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Owl Woman (Papago), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 90, Plate 16a, AFC 1944/002: PH033; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Katcora (Yuma), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 110, Plate 27a, AFC 1944/002: PH034; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Charles Wilson (Yuma), similar to Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 110, Plate 1, AFC 1944/002: PH035; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Sidney Wesley approaching through the woods (Choctaw), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 135, Plate 16, no. 1, AFC 1944/002: PH036; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Sidney Wesley (Choctaw), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 136, Plate 10, no. 1, AFC 1944/002: PH037; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Mary Hickman's house, where songs were recorded (Choctaw), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 135, Plate 16, no. 2, AFC 1944/002: PH038; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Mary Hickman (Choctaw), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 136, Plate 10, no. 2, AFC 1944/002: PH039; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Possibly Everglades, Florida, AFC 1944/002: PH040; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Possibly Everglades, Florida, AFC 1944/002: PH041; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Seminole family, AFC 1944/002: PH042; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Seminole man, AFC 1944/002: PH043; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Seminole woman, AFC 1944/002: PH044; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Everglades, Florida, AFC 1944/002: PH045; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Seminole woman and chickee, AFC 1944/002: PH046; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Seminole chickee, AFC 1944/002: PH047; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Seminole, AFC 1944/002: PH048; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Possibly Seminole garden, AFC 1944/002: PH049; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Seminole woman and chickee, AFC 1944/002: PH050; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Birches and lake, Minnesota, AFC 1944/002: PH051; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Seminole chickee, Everglades, Florida, circa 1932 - circa 1933, AFC 1944/002: PH052; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Love charm, drawing, and words for two love songs, AFC 1944/002: PH053; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Cropped form of AFC 1944/002: PH079 (Box 13)
    - Possibly Chippewa birch-bark dwelling, AFC 1944/002: PH054; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - On Tamiami Trail, circa 1932 - circa 1933, AFC 1944/002: PH055; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Charlie Billie (Seminole), reverse of Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 161, Plate 4a, circa 1932 - circa 1933, AFC 1944/002: PH056; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Seminole man, circa 1932 - circa 1933, AFC 1944/002: PH057; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Pan playing on whistle (Hidatsa), see Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 80, Plate 10a, AFC 1944/002: PH058; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Fred Mart, acted as the writer's interpreter throughout this research, Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 75, AFC 1944/002: PH059; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Slahal game, Chilliwack, British Columbia, circa 1926, AFC 1944/002: PH060; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Portrait of Frances Densmore, 1927, AFC 1944/002: PH061; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Chippewa Midewiwin song mnemonics, Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 45, page 73 (excerpt), AFC 1944/002: PH062; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Dots show places where Densmore studied American Indian music prior to 1930, AFC 1944/002: PH063; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Scene at Neah Bay, Washington, circa 1923 - circa 1926, AFC 1944/002: PH064; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - George Escalanti (Yuma) playing cane flute, Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 110, Plate 26a, circa 1920 - circa 1922, AFC 1944/002: PH065; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Kachora (Yuma), uncropped version of Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 110, Plate 27a, circa 1920 - circa 1922, AFC 1944/002: PH066; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Sioux women dancers, Grand River, North Dakota, circa 1911 - circa 1912, AFC 1944/002: PH067; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - House where songs were recorded (Yaqui), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 110, Plate 21a, circa 1920 - circa 1922, AFC 1944/002: PH068; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Sioux encampment, Grand River, North Dakota, circa 1911 - circa 1912, AFC 1944/002: PH069; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Hillside with saguaro cactus near San Xavier, Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 90, Plate 3b, circa 1920 - circa 1922, AFC 1944/002: PH070; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - River scene, trees draped with Spanish moss, Bayou Teche, Louisiana, circa 1933, AFC 1944/002: PH071; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Young Doctor (Makah), Neah Bay, Washington, Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 124, Plate 1, circa 1923 - circa 1926, AFC 1944/002: PH072; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Makah girl, Neah Bay, Washington, circa 1923 - circa 1926, AFC 1944/002: PH073; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Shore toward Cape Flattery, Neah Bay, Washington, circa 1923 - circa 1926, AFC 1944/002: PH074; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Charles Swan (Makah) in dance costume, Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 124, Plate 4c, circa 1923 - circa 1926, AFC 1944/002: PH075; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
    - Jim Hunter in dance costume, Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 124, Plate 4a, circa 1923 - circa 1926, AFC 1944/002: PH076; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 13)
  - Subseries 2: Glass negatives
    - Captives I am bringing, Eagle Shield's song (Teton Sioux), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, page 396 (excerpt), AFC 1944/002: PH077; 1 glass negative (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 14)
    - Love-charm song sung by Manidogicigokwe (Chippewa), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 45, page 91 (excerpt), AFC 1944/002: PH078; 1 glass negative (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 14)
    - Song pictures for two love-charm songs (Chippewa), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 45, page 90, plus unidentified photograph, AFC 1944/002: PH079; 1 glass negative (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 14)
    - Brave Buffalo (Teton Sioux), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, plate 25, AFC 1944/002: PH080; 1 glass negative (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 14)
    - Eagle Shield (Teton Sioux), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, plate 40, AFC 1944/002: PH081; 1 glass negative (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 14)
    - Song of the shuffling-feet dance (a), sung by Kills-at-Night and his wife, Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, page 478, AFC 1944/002: PH082; 1 glass negative (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 14)
    - Gemiwunac (Chippewa), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 45, plate 9, AFC 1944/002: PH083; 1 glass negative (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 14)
    - Drawing by Eagle Shield (Teton Sioux), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, Plate 65b, AFC 1944/002: PH084; 1 glass negative (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 14)
    - Chippewa Midewiwin song mnemonics, Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 45, songs 103-104, 106-107, pages 114-115, AFC 1944/002: PH085; 1 glass negative (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 14)
    - Sioux woman, AFC 1944/002: PH086; 1 glass negative (6.5 x 4.25 inch) (Box 14)
    - Sioux woman, AFC 1944/002: PH087; 1 glass negative (6.5 x 4.25 inch) (Box 14)
    - Buffalo Boy (Santee-Yanktonai), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, Plate 9 and page 91, AFC 1944/002: PH088; 1 glass negative (7 x 5 inch) (Box 14)
    - Siyaka (Yanktonai-Teton), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, Plate 1, and page 90, AFC 1944/002: PH089; 1 glass negative (7 x 5 inch) (Box 14)
    - Siyaka (Yanktonai Teton), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, see Plate 1 for comparison, AFC 1944/002: PH090; 1 glass negative (7 x 5 inch) (Box 14)
    - Lone Man (Teton Sioux); see different image of Lone Man in Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, Plate 23, AFC 1944/002: PH091; 1 glass negative (7 x 5 inch) (Box 14)
    - White-Buffalo-Walking (Teton Sioux), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, Plate 11, AFC 1944/002: PH092; 1 glass negative (7 x 5 inch) (Box 14)
    - Buffalo Boy (Santee-Yanktonai), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, Plate 9 and page 91, AFC 1944/002: PH093; 1 glass negative (7 x 5 inch) (Box 14)
    - Red Bird (Teton Sioux), uncropped version of Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, Plate 22, AFC 1944/002: PH094; 1 glass negative (7 x 5 inch) (Box 14)
    - No Heart (Yanktonai), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, see Plate 10 for comparison, and page 91, AFC 1944/002: PH095; 1 glass negative (7 x 5 inch) (Box 14)